RAYMOND PHILLIPS

Nashville, TN 37221 Phone: 615-917-8242 | Email: raydphillips3@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/raymond-phillips-5b4208a1/

Github: https://github.com/raydphillips3 | Portfolio: https://raydphillips3.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background of proven experience in new process implantation, quickly adopting new technologies, and technical training and writing, including projects at 2 of the Big 4 Global Consulting firms. Expert at quickly learning systems and applications to analyze for process change, repurposing, and training. Self-motivated combining enthusiasm, strong creative abilities, excellent verbal and written communication skills, and attention to details to develop user-friendly applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: CSS, JavaScript, HTML5

Applications: Bootstrap, Express, Handelbars, iQuery, MongoDB, MySQL, Node.js, and

ReactJS.

PROJECTS

Project: Pets-N-Parents Parade | **Link to Github** | **Link to Deployed Project** [always write out link address]

- Our application aims to connect those who are looking to add a new member of the family with those who want to be confident their pet will continue to be loved and cared for.
- I primarily worked on the front-end of the application. I built the pages and ensured that they link and transition smoothly.
- The application uses React.js, MongoDB, and Materialize CSS.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Analyst 2018 - 2020

TEKsystems (Contracted to KPMG)

Developed, implemented, and delivered content for end-user demonstrations and presentations. Facilitated training for end-users. Assisted in facilitating training of on-site support team and provided on-site support. Utilized and sharpened communication, process development, critical thinking, and route cause analysis skills.

Key Accomplishments:

- Recognized as a top trainer, charged with analyzing, developing, and delivering best practices trainings.
- Sole travel trainer of the training team.

Technical Trainer/Technical Writer

YOH (Contracted to General Electric)

2017 - 2017

Conducted on-site training of local delivery agents on Oracle based order management software implementation. Created documents for workaround processes for the support team. Utilized communication and route cause analysis skills.

Technical Trainer

LRA By Deloitte 2016 – 2017

Facilitated on-site management and associate training, for new software and hardware installation, in a retail store environment. Troubleshooting of technical issues that may have arisen with the install and created workaround documents for the training team. Utilized and sharpened communication, route cause analysis, and process development skills.

Key Accomplishments:

- Recognized as a top trainer and became a 'new trainer' trainer.
- Given special assignments for 90-day installment site evaluations.

Regional Lead/Technical Trainer

TEKsystems (Contracted to Deloitte)

2014 - 2016

Created and updated training materials for the Integrated Eligibility System. Facilitated "Super User" conference calls on a bi-weekly basis, including trouble tickets and a Q & A session. Diagnosed and resolved issues for cases with urgent need on the Rapid-Fire Response Team. On-site support for end-users during Go-Live of the Integrated Eligibility System.

Key Accomplishments:

- Started at the entry level on the project (#2 trainer) and promoted up to a site support regional lead.
- Was the only contractor on the project to:
 - o Be in a regional lead position.
 - o Facilitate trainings in multiple areas of the application.
 - o Develop content. Developed 2 job aids and a training module.

THE KROGER CO. 2009 - 2014

ASSISTANT TRAINING MANAGER /STORE CO-MANAGER

Instrumental in day-to-day store fostering a "Customer First" atmosphere as a mainstay of the store environment. Created Training material for Kroger's prescription writing, processing, and reporting system. Training material included Release Notes for system upgrades, Best Practices and troubleshooting reference documentation, Web Reference Guide, policy and procedure updates, and a weekly newsletter.

Key Accomplishment:

Food Safety Champion of the district.

EDUCATION

Trilogy Full Stack Bootcamp Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills.

University of Dayton - Electronic Engineering Technology / Secondary Education